# **Allan Fernandes** Frontend Developer

• Nottingham, United Kingdom

✓ fernzallan14@gmail.com

+44 07825214865

https://allanfernandes.dev/

#### **PROFILE**

A zealous web developer with over **2 years of frontend experience** and enthusiasm for responsive web-design while also genuinely caring about **user experience** & **accessibility**. Eager to constantly learn new skills and improve tools to maximize productivity.

#### **SKILLS**

#### **Frontend**

HTML5, CSS3, SASS, LESS, JavaScript, jQuery, React, SEO Optimization, Web Hosting, Version Control.

#### **Soft Skills**

Effective programming, communication, and team working skills developed from my studies and work experience as a web developer.

## **Responsive Web Design**

Mobile-first approach focusing on improving user clarity & intuitiveness on smaller devices while also being WCAG compliant.

## **WordPress & Shopify**

Built and deployed eCommerce stores using CMS solutions such as WordPress and Shopify.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

May 2021 – present

This is DMG ☑

Germany

Front-end Developer, Working remotely for a German-based tech startup as a frontend developer creating interfaces for international clients.

- Created accessible, responsive, and functional user interfaces to allow users on any device to have the same perfect user experience.
- Collaborated with product team members to implement new feature developments.

#### Sep 2020 – May 2021

## Mumbai, India

#### **The Starter Labs**

Web Developer

- Built mock designs and wireframes for landing pages for 5 new product concepts and start-ups.
- Accessed UX & UI designs for technical feasibility.

## Mar 2019 – Aug 2020

## Mumbai, India

### **Unifynd Technologies** 🗷

Junior Web Developer

- Nhance: ☐ Built visual interfaces for one of India's leading retail merchant's (Phoenix market city's) reward program, involving admin dashboards, and website components.
- **Unifynd :** Parent company website revamp.
- **UDC** ☑: Handling user registration and submission for an online product design hackathon.

#### **EDUCATION**

## Sep 2021 – present

Nottingham, UK

## **MSc Computer Science**

**Nottingham Trent University** 

**Key Modules:** 

- Systems Analysis & Design.
- Mobile Interactive Systems.
- · Advanced Software Engineering.

Jun 2018

## St. Xavier's College Autonomous

Mumbai, India

Bachelor's in Information Technology (BSc IT)

GPA: 2.79/4

#### **REFERENCES**

References available upon request.